一千年前…
一群织布工组织了一个秘密的刺客集团
他们通过暗杀活动  使濒临崩溃的世界恢复秩序
他们自称为"兄弟会"
六个星期前…
韦斯利·吉布森  没有结果
无法处理您的交易
资金不足  你是个混蛋
你没钱了  你最好的朋友在操你女朋友
你知道  可是你这软蛋什么也做不了
正确---- 错误---
黑帮在屋顶火拚 五人被乱枪打死
去你妈的
摄像头摄下嫌犯面容
通缉犯
17号织造厂
生日快乐  亲爱的贾妮丝
Happy birthday, dear Janice
祝你生日快乐
Happy birthday to you!
正在过生日的是我那得了厌食症的老板
It's my anorexic boss' birthday.
这意味着各个办公室的人  都在某种程度的压力下
This means there's a certain amount of inter-office pressure
被迫站到会议桌边
to stand around the conference table
一边吃着垃圾食品  一边假装崇拜她
eating crappy food and pretending to worship her.
真好吃
That's so good.
要在整整五分钟里  忘记贾妮丝对大家的残酷压迫
WESLEY: Acting for five minutes like Janice doesn't make all our lives miserable
这是我一天里最困难的工作
is the hardest work I'll do all day.
我的工作头衔是账户经理
My job title is account manager.
以前我的工作是叫做账户服务代表
I used to be called an account service representative,
可是有个顾问说  我们需要的是管理客户
but a consultant told us we needed to manage our clients
而不是给他们服务
and not service them.
我有个女朋友  我对她既没有管理也没有服务
I have a girlfriend whom I neither manage nor service.
我最要好的朋友巴里  正在一张宜家牌餐桌上操她
That's my best friend, Barry, fucking her on an IKEA kitchen table
那张桌子是我用很实惠的价钱淘来的
I picked up for a really good price.
我发现最近我很难在乎什么事了
I'm finding it hard to care about anything these days.
事实上  我唯一在乎的事就是  我对任何事情都关心不起来
In fact, the only thing I do care about is the fact that I can't care about anything.
真的  这让我很担心
Seriously. It worries me.
我叫韦斯利·吉布森
My name is Wesley Gibson.
我出生才七天  爸爸就扔下妈妈跑了
My dad walked out on my mom when I was seven days old.
有时我想  也许他曾经望着宝贝儿子的蓝眼睛  扪心自问
Sometimes I wonder if he ever looked into my baby blues eyes and asked himself,
我就是这个21世纪头号废柴的老爸吗
"Did I just father the most insignificant asshole of the 21st century?"
好  要是你能在28号以前把托卖的  货物给我  对
Well, if you could get me the consignment to me by the 28th... Yeah.
你面前有号码吗
Do you have the numbers in front of you?
别紧张
MR x: Relax.
如果出现的是你的名字  你早就死了
If your name had come up, you'd be dead already.
我们最近有一些意外的损失
We've had some unexpected losses recently.
我们想知道
We'd like to know
我们的对头是从哪里搞到军火的
where our competitor is getting his munition.
很干净
It's clean.
什么意思
Meaning?
意思就是没法追查来源
Meaning it's untraceable.
你的对头非常聪明
Your competitor's very smart.
卧倒
Get down!
我操
Fuck it.
没有人能脱离兄弟会  "十字架"
No one leaves the Fraternity, Cross.
我对兄弟会有了新的看法
I have a new perspective on the Fraternity.
小心点
MR x: Careful.
你不可能毁掉存在了一千年的组织
You don't destroy something that's been around for a thousand years.
组织已经毁了  他破坏了法典
It's already destroyed. He broke the code.
我不能不阻止
I have to stop this.
真的  你明白
Really? You know this.
那为什么你不肯亲自来面对我
So why don't you face me yourself?
千万别派小绵羊来杀大灰狼
Never send sheep to kill a wolf.
他们只是幌子
CROSS: They were just the decoys.
再见  X先生
Goodbye, Mr x.
千万别派小绵羊来杀大灰狼
Never send sheep to kill a wolf.
他们只是幌子
They were just the decoys.
韦斯利
Wesley!
怎么啦
What is it?
什么怎么啦  听啊
What do you mean, "What is it"? Listen.
这么吵  你叫我怎么睡得着
Well, how am I suppose to sleep with all that fucking racket?
老是被这鬼东西吵醒  我们到底什么时候搬家
When are we gonna move so we don't have to wake up to that shit?
我倒是有点喜欢这声音
I kind of like it.
它可以淹没你那讨厌的破嗓门
WESLEY: It helps to drown out the sound of your annoying, fucking voice.
现在求求你  让我睡吧
Now, please, let me sleep.
你到底有没有考虑过我们谈的事
Have you even thought about our talk?
嗯
Yes.
哪一次
Which one?
好极了  好极了
Perfect. That's perfect.
给安娜贝尔喂食
Feed Annabelle.
对不起
Sorry.
哦  我的天哪
Oh, my fucking God.
但愿你桌上那个东西  不是我要的结算报告
I hope that's not my billing report sitting on your desk.
真像供桌上的一泡大便
Holy shit on an altar, it is.
一小时内把报告交到我桌上
I want that report on my desk in one hour.
好吧  各位  我们还要加班一小时…
Okay, everybody, we're all gonna stay an extra hour...
想听点惨事吗
Want to hear something sad?
我必须使用人体工程学键盘才能让  重复性压抑的危害不至于太大
I need an ergonomic keyboard to keep my repetitive stress injury in check.
我的重复性工作多得让我压抑  真他妈的惨
Just the fact that I repeat something enough that it causes me stress is fucking sad.
干得好  哥们  看见巴里没有
Nice job, dude. You seen Barry?
他又去看牙医了
He had to go to the dentist. Again.
是啊
Yes!
巴里
Barry!
你说他们这里有没有事后避孕药
You think they have that morning-after pill here?
那东西很有用  碾碎了掺在荷包蛋里面
That thing works. Crush it up, put it in her omelette,
"嘿  宝贝  在床上吃早餐吧"  小心一点总没坏处
"Hey, baby, breakfast in bed." You can never be too safe.
哦  老天
Oh, God.
我把钱包丢了
I lost my wallet somewhere.
这些都算在一起
All this together?
不  不  是的
No, no. Yes.
他是好汉
He is the man.
一共多少  哦  再加上这个
How much is it? Oh. Plus this.
20.42美元
$20.42.
西瓜味
Watermelon.
妞都喜欢
Chicks dig it.
谢谢
Thanks.
下回见
See you next time.
祝你晚上过得愉快
PHARMACIST: Have a good night.
我真喜欢这些能量饮料
I love these energy drinks, man.
我简直是在用能量饮料洗胃
I'm almost, like, kind of on an energy drink cleanse,
早饭时喝一罐  中饭时又要喝两三罐
where I do one for breakfast and then, like, two or three for lunch.
我是好汉
I'm the man?
对啊  巴里  我是好汉
Yeah, right, Barry, I'm the man.
事实上  我真是了不起的好汉
In fact, I'm so much the man,
要靠不停地吃药来防止焦虑症发作
I have a standing prescription for medication to control my anxiety attacks.
天哪  但愿有什么别的东西能缓解我的压力
God, I wish I had something else to relieve my stress.
你好  韦斯利
Hello, Wesley.
你知道  有些人  是美人
You know, there are people, beautiful people,
你只希望她们能在别样的环境下  别样的地方看到你
you just wish they could see you in a different setting, a different place,
不是在这个鬼地方看你  不是看你这副鬼样
instead of where you are, what you've become.
妮可长得太赞啦
Nicole is so hot.
什么
What?
被她雷到啦
Boom goes the dynamite.
不过大多数时候  你希望自己不是那么废柴
WESLEY: But most of all, you wish you weren't such a pussy
不该企盼不可能发生的改变
for wishing for things that will never change.
全能的好上帝啊  你是在他妈的度春假吗
JANICE: Good God A'mighty, you're over here like it's spring fucking break,
我到现在还没拿到那份结算报告
and I still don't have that billing report.
我到底为什么养你  韦斯利
Why do I even keep you around, Wesley?
我会做完的  贾妮丝
I'll get it done, Janice.
好像我以前没听过这话一样  "我会做完的"
Like I never heard that before. "I'll get it done."
我会做完的  我会做完的  我会做完的
"I'll get it done. I'll get it done, Janice.
我会做完的
"I'll get it done."
你就没什么要说的
Why don't you have anything to say for yourself?
对不起
I'm sorry.
哦  你这废物
Well, you're worthless.
我才应该说对不起  因为我雇了你这蠢驴
I'm the one who's sorry I hired your ass.
知道一天结束时最妙的一点是什么吗
You know what the best thing is about the end of the day?
明天又要从头再来一遍
Tomorrow it starts all over again.
嗨  你好吗  很好
Hi. How you doing? Good.
对不起  你道歉次数太多了
I'm sorry? You apologise too much.
我很抱歉
Sorry about that.
我认识你父亲
I knew your father.
我出生第一周  父亲就跑了  所以…
My father left the week I was born, so...
你父亲昨天在大都会大厦的屋顶上死了
Your father died yesterday on the rooftop of the Metropolitan Building.
对不起
Sorry.
你看  酒吧就在那边  所以…
Look, the liquor rounds are just over there, so...
你父亲是有史以来最优秀的刺客之一
Your father was one of the greatest assassins who ever lived.
杀他的人就在你背后
The man who killed him is behind you.
别错过
最后的机会
那家伙乱开枪…
This guy's just shooting up...
对不起  对不起
Sorry. Sorry.
什么… 哦  上帝哦  上帝  刚才到底怎么回事
What... Oh, my God! Oh, my God! What the fuck just happened?
拜托  拜托  拜托  你开快点
Please! Please! Please drive faster.
拜托你安静  拜托  拜托开快点
Please be quiet. Please drive... Please drive faster.
请你  请你明白  我对自己的性命很在乎
Please... Please understand that I care about my life!
我不知道你干了什么事  把那家伙惹毛了
I don't know what the fuck you did to piss this guy off,
可是你得让我逃出去叫警察啊
but you're gonna have to let me out and call the cops!
嘿   嘿
Hey! Hey!
你干什么哦  操  你疯了吗
What are you doing? Oh, shit! Are you crazy?
哦  操
Oh, shit!
我看我们甩掉他了  我们甩掉他了
I think we lost him. I think we lost him.
在下一个街角让我下车  好吗
Could you let me out at the next corner, please?
操
Shit!
我操
Fuck!
哦  操
Oh, shit!
他就在那边
He's right there!
我是个会计  我只是个会计
Look, I'm an accountant. I'm just an accountant.
我操
Oh, fuck!
他还真是死心眼
He's fucking persistent, you know.
我操
Fuck!
给他点颜色瞧瞧
You kick his ass!
打他
Shoot him!
你干什么  你打自己的车干什么
What are you doing? What are you shooting our car for, huh?
你疯了吗  抓住方向盘
Are you crazy? Grab the wheel.
你要去哪
WESLEY: Where are you going?
回来
Get back in here!
哦  上帝
Oh, my God!
该死的对不起
Oh, damn! I'm sorry.
枪  什么
Gun! What?
在座位底下
Under the seat!
给
Here.
哦  操
Oh, shit!
操
Shit!
当心  让开
Look out! Get out!
当心哦  上帝
Look out! Oh, my God!
操
Shit!
对不起
I'm sorry!
在你后面
Behind you!
我操
Fuck.
操  操
Shit. Shit.
你好
Hello.
我没有钱  也没有…
I don't have any money or...
我还以为他的个子要
I thought he'd be
高一点
taller.
Taller?
先生…
Sir...
先生  我一直在对这位女士解释  我是个会计
Sir, I've been trying to explain to the lady here that I'm an accountant.
我是账户服务代表  我是账户经理
I'm an account service representative... I'm an account manager.
要是你们打电话给我的老板  贾妮丝
And I'm sure that if you call my boss, Janice,
她肯定会帮你们解决问题
she'd fill you in on whatever has gone wrong.
你们可以给她发电子邮件或者  她会帮你们解决的
You can contact her by email or... She'll put you straight.
把苍蝇的翅膀打下来
Shoot the wings off the flies.
我不知道这是什么意思
I don't know what that means.
把苍蝇的翅膀打下来
Shoot the wings off the flies.
你们肯定是把我当成别人了
I really think you have me mixed up with somebody else.
我数到三
On three.
你不开枪  我就开枪
Either you shoot, or I do.
一
One.
好吧
Okay.
二
Two.
我连看都看不清
I can't even see them!
三
Three.
好了  好了
Okay. Okay.
这不可能
That's impossible.
在今天以前  有很多事情对你来说是不可能的
SLOAN: A lot of things for you weren't possible before today.
韦斯利  你刚才体会到的  并不是恐慌症发作
What you experienced, Wesley, was not a panic attack.
你的心脏每分钟跳了400多下
Your heart was beating in excess of 400 beats per minute,
使你的血液里充满了肾上腺素
sending abundant amounts of adrenaline into your bloodstream.
这就使你能比常人更快地观察和反应
This allows you to see and react faster than normal.
全世界能做到的人只有区区几个
Only a few people in the world can do that.
你父亲能做到  你也能做到
Your father could do it and you can do it.
稍微锻炼一下  你就能学会控制这样的发作
With a little work, you can learn to control these attacks.
离我远点
Stay away from me.
你离我远点
Just stay back from me.
我有枪  先生  明白吗
I have a gun, sir. All right?
我叫斯隆
My name is Sloan.
这位是狐狸
This is Fox.
在你周围的其他人都是杀人高手
And the others you see around you are all very good at killing.
所以呢  如果我是你  我会一直把枪指着我
So, if I were you, I'd keep the gun pointed at me.
用枪指着他们是没有好果子吃的
You don't wanna point it at any of them.
你这样比较好
That's better.
你是疯子  不
You're insane. No.
真正的疯狂是  明明体内流着杀手之血
Insanity is wasting your life as a nothing
却碌碌无为地虚度光阴
when you have the blood of a killer flowing in your veins.
真正的疯狂是  心中关着一头猛狮
Insanity is being shit on, beat down,
手里掌握了释放它的钥匙
coasting through life in a miserable existence
却甘心被欺侮  被打败  浑浑噩噩地过着悲惨的人生
when you have a caged lion locked inside and a key to release it.
你手里的这把枪是伊玛尼什17型  它本来是你父亲的
This gun you're holding is an lmanishi 17. It belonged to your father.
他可以用它演奏交响乐
He could conduct a symphony orchestra with it.
你将用它杀死  残忍地枪杀你父亲的凶手
And you're going to use it to kill the man who shot him down in cold blood.
我不能  今天晚上想杀你的人也是他
I can't... The same man who tried to kill you tonight.
你父亲是我们的一员
Your father was one of us.
我们是刺客兄弟会  命运的武器
A fraternity of assassins. The weapons of fate.
我们已经把他的所有财产都转到你名下
We've transferred all of his assets over to you.
我向你保证   数目非常可观
And let me assure you, they are substantial.
这就是你等待了很久的命运
It is your long-awaited destiny
加入我们
to join us.
你退后  退后
Back off. Back off.
你对我一点也不了解
You don't know anything about me.
离我远点  离我远点
Stay away from me. Stay away from me.
你离我远点
You stay away from me?
你离我远点  好吗  让我过去  行不行
You stay away from me, please? Will you let me through?
有时候做了一个梦  迷迷糊糊醒过来
You know when you have a dream and you're half awake,
那个梦仍然在脑海里  挥之不去
but it's still in the fringe of your brain?
这时候你睁开眼睛  发现那只是个梦  就会乐得打滚
Then you open your eyes and you're so damn glad it was a dream.
这一次可不是梦
This was nothing like that.
对不起  你等我一下好吗  谢谢
I'm sorry. Could you just give me one second? Thank you.
哦  操
Oh, shit.
韦斯利
Wesley.
你怎么了
What's up with you?
你什么意思
What do you mean?
你  你来得很早
You're... You're here early.
你  你看起来精神很好
Is... You seem a little pepped up.
你好吗  嗯  很好
You all right? Well, yeah.
很好
Yeah.
我觉得自己
I guess I feel
有点不一样了
kind of different.
随你怎么说吧  我要去拿点报事贴  要帮你拿一叠吗
Whatever. I'm gonna go get some Post-it Notes. Do you want one?
不用  真的
No. Really?
对  好吧
Yeah. Okay.
天哟  地哟  亲娘老子哟  我到现在还没拿到结算报告
Jesus H. Fucking Popsicle, I still don't have my billing reports,
你倒有闲工夫坐在这里上网
but you've got time to sit here and Google your ass off.
哦  我知道一件事
Well, I know one thing.
下星期就要评审你的表现
You've got your review coming up next week,
我是巴不得早一点扣你工资啊
and I can't wait to start checking me off some big fucking boxes.
工作态度  差  绩效  差
Attitude, poor! Performance, poor!
管理能力  差
Management skills, poor!
与他人的合作  那是天大的笑话
Works well with others. That's a fucking joke.
这是什么乱七八糟的   这家伙是谁
What is this bullshit? Who's this prick?
有几个废柴在大楼上被人爆了头
Some loser gets his head blown off at the Metropolitan...
闭上你的臭嘴
Shut the fuck up!
她当了一个芝麻绿豆大的官
She has one single iota of tenuous power.
就以为可以把大家当佣人使唤
She thinks she can push everyone around.
你不需要这个
You don't need this.
我能理解
I understand.
国中的日子肯定不好过
Junior high must have been kind of tough,
可是这不等于说  你有权让员工做牛做马  贾妮丝
but it doesn't give you the right to treat your workers like horseshit, Janice.
我知道大家都在笑你  贾妮丝
I know we laugh at you, Janice.
我们都知道你在办公桌最上面的抽屉里  藏了很多果酱甜甜圈
We all know you keep your stash of jelly doughnuts in the top drawer of your desk.
可是我要告诉你
But I want you to know
如果你不是那么招人厌  我们会同情你的
if you weren't such a bitch, we'd feel sorry for you.
我真的有点同情你
I do feel sorry for you.
可是考虑到你的表现
But as it stands, the way you behave,
我觉得我可以代表整个办公室的人
I feel I can speak for the entire office
对你说
when I tell you
吃屎去吧
go fuck yourself.
太强了  谁是好汉
Yeah. That was great, bro. Who's the man?
我是好汉
I'm the man.
这是个坏主意
That's a bad idea.
找不到你的钥匙了吗
Couldn't find your keys, huh?
这一手可能很有用  你会教我吗
That could be handy. You going to teach me that?
我也许用得着
I might need that.
你叫  狐狸  对吧  那是什么  是代号吗
So, Fox, right? What is that? Is that a call sign?
就像《壮志凌云》里的"小牛"
Is it like Maverick in Top Gun?
你要是告诉我真名  就得杀了我
You could tell me, but you'd have to kill me?
我开玩笑的
I'm just kidding.
彼得
Peter!
检查一下这台STB的梭子转速  应该是每分钟300转
Check the shuttle rotation on this STB. It should be 300 per minute.
这种棉织品的相反丝线应该是4000根
This kind of cotton weave, the opposing thread count should be 4,000.
嘿   真了不起
Hey, this is pretty awesome, huh?
这是幌子吗
Is it a front?
什么东西的幌子  我不知道
Front for what? I don't know.
暗杀吧
Assassinations.
你也许以为这是用来掩盖的幌子
You may think this is a front for something,
我只能告诉你这是一个纺织厂
all I can tell you is this is a textile mill.
乔治… 乔治  去帮彼得一下
And George... George, go help Peter up there.
好
Yeah.
这是个纺织厂
This is a textile mill.
而且很不错
And a damn good one.
哦  妙极了  不过那是骗人的吧
WESLEY: Yeah, that's cute, but that's bullshit, right?
我是说  这些人都是杀手吧  对吗
I mean, all these guys are killers, aren't they?
我觉得你该回答我几个问题
I think you owe me some answers.
好吧  我显然是不懂
All right. Clearly I don't understand,
你们是做毛衣的还是杀人的
but do you make sweaters or do you kill people?
喝杯咖啡问了这么多问题
That's an awful lot of questions over coffee.
你真的准备好听答案了吗
Are you sure you're ready for the answers?
是的
Yes, I'm sure.
我没法回头了
I can't go back.
不可能回到原来的生活
Not to my life.
他归你了
He's all yours.
好  咱们走
All right. We're up.
你好吗
How you doing?
我是修补匠
I'm The Repairman.
你修补什么
What do you repair?
一辈子的坏习惯
A lifetime of bad habits.
好吧  你帮我个忙好吗
Okay. Would you do me a favour?
把你的手臂放到身后
Just put your arms behind your back.
没事的  我不知道
It's okay. I don't know...
放到背后  这样就行
Just behind your back. Is this okay?
放松
Just relax.
这也是训练
Is this part of it?
我们开始吧
REPAIRMAN: There we go.
你要在我头上套个口袋  不  不用口袋
You going to put a bag over my head? No. There's no need for a bag.
不会太紧吧  不  这样很好
That's not too tight, is it? No, that's nice.
你为什么来这里  韦斯利
Why did you come here, Wesley?
是你带我来的  你忘了
Well, you brought me here, remember?
你他妈的干什么
What the fuck did you do that...
修理工打了他几下
How many punches did The Repairman throw
才开始数绵羊的
before he was counting sheep?
以前我的脸被打的次数不多  明白吗
Well, I haven't spent a lot of time having my face smashed in before, all right?
你用刀的次数多吗  早饭  中饭和晚饭时都用
Did you spend a lot of time with knives? At breakfast, lunch and dinner.
操
Fuck.
刚才那是个反问句   蠢驴
It was a rhetorical question, culo.
你要是再插嘴   我就用刀刃抽你
You interrupt me again, I use the business end.
他妈的  现在你听好了
Here's what you need to know, puto.
刀子很容易隐藏
Knives are easy to hide.
它们不会卡壳  也永远不会用光子弹
They don't jam and they never run out of bullets.
如果你要做近距离接触的工作
They come in handy
刀子是非常好用的
when you have to do some close contact work.
这是怎么回事  老兄
What the fuck, man?
过来  过来  啥
Come here. Come here. What?
现在  试着砍我  什么
Now, try to cut me. What?
试着砍我  喂
Try to cut me. Hey!
就用那个戳我  你当心点  这刀很快
Just stick me with that... Be careful with that. That's sharp.
你就戳  戳  戳   为什么
Just stick and stick and stick. Why?
说真的  老兄  我可能会弄伤你  喂
Seriously, man, I could hurt you. Hey!
好吧  娘娘腔
Okay, pussy.
我不是娘娘腔  你就是娘娘腔
I'm not a pussy. You're a pussy.
不   我不是娘娘腔  你就是娘娘腔
No, I'm not a pussy. You're a pussy!
我不是娘娘腔  我只是在意你的健康状况
I'm not a pussy. I got a healthy respect for the human condition.
放屁  娘娘腔  我不是娘娘腔
Fuck that, you pussy! I'm not a pussy!
你就是娘娘腔  我不是娘娘腔
You're a pussy! I'm not a pussy!
来吧  娘娘腔   我不是娘娘腔
Come on, pussy. I'm not a pussy!
嗨   你好吗
Hi. How you doing?
怎么回事
What the fuck?
操
The fuck!
稍等一下   稍等一下
Just a moment. Just a moment.
对不起
Sorry.
喂   喂
WESLEY: Hello? Hey!
回来  喂
Hey, come back! Hey!
你一定要喝下去  喝下去  对
You must drink. Drink. Yeah.
这是什么  这里是康复室
What is this? This is the recovery room.
这种药浴可以刺激白血球  加快康复
This bath stimulates white blood cells and speed up the process.
在这里  瘀伤  刀伤  骨折只要几个小时就能好  不用等上几天
In here, bruises, cuts, breaks heal in hours, not days.
你骗我吧
You shitting me?
这是什么  伏特加  对
What is that? Vodka? Yeah.
你是俄罗斯人   对
Are you Russian? Yeah.
起来
Get up.
这是枪匠
This is The Gunsmith.
他对枪械的了解比任何人都多  他会教你怎么用枪
He knows more about a piece than anybody, and he's gonna teach you how to use one.
你好吗  很好
How you doing? Pretty good.
你知道吗塞尔查的腿断了  哦  真的
You know that Seltzer broke his leg? Oh, really?
真的  断了三处
Yeah, in three places.
怎么会的  从大楼上跳下来摔的
How'd he do that? Jumped off a building.
那他还好吧  还行  不过伤势挺重的
FOx: So, is he okay? GUNSMITH: Yeah. It's pretty bad, though.
哦  上帝
Oh, my God.
哦  上帝  这做得太像真的了
Oh, my God, you guys, that is so realistic.
他已经在康复室呆了三天
He's been in recovery for, like, three days now,
他们说还不能让他出来
and they say they're not even gonna let him out.
哦  上帝
Oh, my God.
Oh, my God!
喂  我们不能开枪打死掉的女人  也许她是什么人的妈妈…
Hey, we can't shoot a dead woman! She might be somebody's mom...
你必须了解子弹打在人身上是什么样的
You need to know what it's like to put a bullet in a body.
你为什么来这儿
Why are you here?
你知道  我以为我是来学习  当超级刺客的
You know, I thought I was learning to be some kind of super assassin.
如果我想挨揍
You know, if I wanted to get beat up,
我就会呆在自己的小办公室隔间里了
I would have stayed in my cubicle, you know.
操
Fuck.
好  射靶子
FOx: All right, shoot the target.
从那里射
From there.
你要我射穿死猪  我要你让子弹拐弯
You want me shoot through Wilbur? I want you to curve the bullet.
我怎么才能做到
How am I suppose to do that?
你要问的不是怎么做
It's not a question of how,
而是做什么
it's a question of what.
如果没有人告诉你子弹是走直线的
If no one told you that bullets flew straight
我给你一把抢  让你去射靶子
and I gave you a gun and told you to hit the target,
你会做什么
what would you do?
让你的直觉来引导你
Let your instincts guide you.
他到底是怎么做到的
How the hell did he do that?
你能做到吗  你能做到吗  喂
Can you do that? Can you do that? Hello?
嘿  我觉得那火车是我的老相识
Hey, I think that's my old train.
现在也是
Still is.
操你混蛋
Shit! You fucking asshole!
来吧
Come on!
咱们走
Let's go.
你是不是疯了
Are you out of your fucking mind?
哦  操  哦  操  哦  操  哦  操
Oh, shit. Oh, shit. Oh, shit. Oh, shit.
哦  上帝  我觉得  我觉得  我觉得
Oh, God, I feel... I feel... I feel...
我觉得有点爽
I feel kind of good.
他干掉了裂嘴  完美的一枪  不可思议的角度
He got Rictus. Perfect shot. Impossible angle.
十字架正在一个一个地杀我们
Cross is taking us out one by one.
韦斯利是唯一能做掉他的人
And Wesley is the only one who can get to him.
每过一个小时   十字架都会走近一步
Cross gets closer with each hour.
回去工作
Get back to work.
看见那个吗
See that?
那是个梭子  对
It's a shuttle. Okay.
我要你想办法抓住它
I want you to try and catch it.
你要我把手伸进去
You want me to stick my hand in there?
对  我要你抓住它
Yes. I want you to catch it.
你要不要拿枪顶住我的头
You wanna put a gun to my head?
那样的话  我眼里的东西就会像苍蝇一样变慢
I can just slow things down like with the flies.
你必须学会自己控制这种能力
You need to learn to control that by yourself.
操  操  操
Fuck, fuck, fuck!
这是狗屎   我操
This is bullshit! Fuck this!
韦斯利  今天好吗
How's it going today, Wesley?
不好  我操织布机  我操修补匠
No. Fuck the loom and fuck The Repairman!
我能打掉苍蝇的翅膀  我已经准备好了
I can shoot the wings off the back of a fly! I'm ready!
等到狐狸说你准备好了  你才算是准备好了
You're ready when Fox says you're ready.
谁让她负责的  我
Who put her in charge? I did.
韦斯利
Wesley.
别人都以为要抓这些小美人  得用奶酪
People think you use cheese to catch these beauties.
其实它们见到花生酱就会发疯
But they go apeshit for peanut butter.
你父亲特别爱玩这个  瞧
Your father was a big fan of this. Watch.
塑性炸药和花生酱
Plastic explosive and peanut butter!
对不起了  米奇
Sorry, Mickey.
五  四  三  二  一
Five, four, three, two, one.
嘿  嘿  俄国人
Hey. Hey, Russian.
这一只很不错
Good for one. Yeah.
要是有一千只会怎样  想想吧
Imagine if you had a thousand.
他们也狠狠地整过你  对吗
They really fucked you up, didn't they?
他们对你做过什么
What the hell did they do to you?
无缘无故把你扔到高速火车上
Throw you in front of a moving train for no reason?
打得你屁滚尿流
Beat the shit out of you?
你知道  你可以说出来的  这地方是狗屎  是狗屎  对吗
You know, you can say it, this place is bullshit. It's bullshit, huh?
狗屎
Bullshit!
五分钟以后  修补匠
Repairman. Five minutes.
你就不能警告我一下
Heads up out of the question?
我操
Fuck.
你他妈的在浪费我的时间  你为什么来这儿
You're a waste of my fucking time! Why are you here?
我不知道  你打我吧
I don't know, so hit me.
你为什么来这儿  我活得猪狗不如  为什么不来这儿
Why are you here? I had a shit life, so why wouldn't I?
我要好好揍你一顿
I wanna kick your fucking ass!
告诉我吧  你要我说什么
Tell me what you want me to say.
你为什么来这儿  我不知道
Why are you here? I don't know!
你为什么来这儿
Why are you here?
你为什么来这儿   我不知道为什么来这儿
Why are you here? I don't know why I'm here.
你为什么来这儿
Why are you here?
我不知道我是谁
I don't know who I am.
你说什么  我说
What did you say? I said...
我说   我不知道我是谁
I said I don't know who I am.
你真的想知道你是谁
Do you really want to know who you are?
这是我的房间
Yeah. It's my room.
不
No.
这是你父亲的房间
This was your father's room.
出了什么事
WESLEY: What happened?
兄弟会的一个成员造反了
SLOAN: A member of this fraternity went rogue.
十字架
Cross.
他一开始就杀了一个比他优秀的人
He started by killing the one man who was better than him.
你父亲
Your father.
十字架在屋顶上偷袭他
Blindsided him on a rooftop.
背叛了他
Betrayed him.
这个房间里的一切
Everything in this room,
书  武器  衣服
books, weapons, clothes,
都是他的
belonged to him.
现在归你了
Now they belong to you.
在这个房间里试着了解他  韦斯利
Find a connection in this room, Wesley.
也许只有靠这个方法  才能弄明白你是谁
It may be the only way of finding out who you are.
现在我知道了  为什么我以前对什么事都不在乎
Now I know why I could never care about anything before this.
我以前的生活是虚伪的
I was living a lie.
我终于有机会穿上父亲的鞋子
Finally, I have a chance to step into my father's shoes.
我成了男子汉  过上了我天生该过的生活
Grow a pair. Live the life I was born to live.
我之前还一直在逃避它  把它当成了又一份该死的结算报告
I've been pissing it all away like it was another fucking billing report.
我应该更努力地训练
I have to train harder.
我要和父亲一样优秀
I have to be as good as my father.
韦斯利  这些架子上放的  是兄弟会的刺杀记录
On these shelves, Wesley, are the records of the Fraternity kills,
要杀你的目标  所有的信息都可以在这里找
everything you will need to kill your target.
要杀十字架
To kill Cross,
要杀那个背叛兄弟会  杀害我父亲的人  我必须做好准备
the man who betrayed the Fraternity and murdered my father, I must prepare.
我必须成为他的学生  记住他的每一次行动
I have to become his student, memorise every move he ever made,
他的每一次刺杀
every attack he ever executed.
他曾经在被特勤局特工包围的  密闭房间里杀掉了一个病人
When he dropped a patient in an airtight room surrounded by Secret Service agents.
他曾经在电梯里干掉了那个商人
When he took out that businessman in the elevator.
当然了  他的子弹是无迹可寻的
His bullets untraceable, of course.
不管他消灭目标时用的是什么武器  什么方法
Or how no matter what the weapon or how he eliminated his target,
他总是棋高一着
he was always one chess move ahead.
多留一手
One move more prepared.
先到一步
One step quicker.
先中一枪
One shot more precise.
事实上  我研究了那么多材料  发现他在杀人时从不失手
In fact, in all my research, I found that he never missed a target.
除了杀我那次
Not until me.
韦斯利  你这辈子第一次能控制了
First time in your life, Wesley, you're in control.
射靶子
Shoot the target.
你疯了
You're crazy.
欢迎加入兄弟会
Welcome to the Fraternity.
我们叫它天命织布机
We call this the Loom of Fate.
过了今天  你就再也不能走进这里
After today, you will never set foot in here again.
为什么
Why not?
因为你就和耶稣的门徒一样
Because, like an apostle,
你的任务不是阐释  而是传达
your task is not to interpret, but to deliver.
历史上每一个文明都有一套密码
Every culture in history has a secret code,
那是在传统文字中找不到的
one you won't find in traditional texts.
一千年前
A thousand years ago,
一群织布工发现  织物中隐藏着一种神秘的语言
a clan of weavers discovered a mystical language hidden in the fabric.
他们自称为 "兄弟会"
They called themselves the Fraternity.
跟你说实话  我只看见一根根线
I'll be honest with you, all I see are threads.
过来
Come here.
看那儿
Look there.
你有没有看见  有一根线织得不合规律
Do you see that one thread that missed the weave
盖在了其他线上面
and lies on top of the others?
这是出错了  不  这是密码
Like a mistake? No, it's a code.
如果垂直线在上  那就是一
If the vertical thread is on top, it's a one.
如果在下  那就是零
If it's below, it's a zero.
二进制代码
Binary code?
内容是什么
What does it say?
是个名字
It's a name.
一个目标
A target.
那些名字是哪来的
Where do the names come from?
是因必要而产生的  韦斯利
Come out of a necessity, Wesley.
为了平卫这个世界的必要
A necessity to maintain balance in the world.
它们是必须被执行的命令
They are orders that must be executed,
我们被赋予在混乱中创造平静的使命
entrusted to us so that we might forge stability out of chaos.
这个是你的
This one is yours.
我不…
I don't...
听好  我以为你带我来这里杀十字架
Look, I thought you brought me here to kill Cross.
你会杀的
You will.
等时间到的时候
In time.
这是你的第一项任务
This is your first assignment.
纺织机提供任务
The loom provides,
由我解读
I interpret,
由你执行
you deliver.
你要我去杀罗伯·迪恩·达登
You want me to kill Robert Deane Darden?
不是我
Not me.
是命运
Fate.
目标将会在会议室里 坐在主席座上
The target will be in the conference room, sitting at the head chair.
总共有六个窗户
There are six windows.
你会从第五扇窗户射入
You will shoot through the fifth.
第五扇窗
Fifth window.
现在
Now.
他做了什么非死不可的事
What did he do that he deserves to die?
你不知道
You don't know.
我不知道他做了什么坏事  也不知道他有多邪恶
I don't know if he was bad, I don't know if he was evil.
我对他一无所知
I don't know anything about him.
我们从纺织机接收命令
We get our orders from a loom.
命运
Fate.
我们只能盲目地相信自己做的是对的
And we're supposed to take it on faith that what we're doing is right.
去杀我们根本不知道的人
Killing someone we know nothing about,
我不知道我能不能做到
I don't know if I can do that.
大约20年前
About 20 years ago,
有一个女孩
there was this girl.
她爸爸是联邦法官
Her dad was a federal judge,
所以她大概从小就认为  自己长大也会当法官
so she probably had it in her mind that she was gonna follow in his footsteps.
有一次她回家过圣诞节
So she's home one Christmas,
她爸爸正在办一件诈欺案
and her dad's on this big racketeering case.
被告想要换个较心软的法官
The defendants want to get a softer judge.
可以被他们收买的法官
One they can buy off.
所以他们雇用了一个人
So they hire this guy,
这个人叫做麦克斯·佩特里吉
Max Petridge,
让他去拜访她爸爸
get him to pay her father a visit.
而他拜访人的方法
And the way he pays people a visit
就是闯入对方家里
is to break in
绑起他的家人
And tie up their loved ones,
然后强迫他们看
and force them to watch
他活活烧死他的目标
while he burns his targets alive.
然后他会拿铁丝制衣架  把它卷起来
And then he takes a wire hanger and twists it round
把他名字的简写烙印在他们身上  让他们永生难忘
and brands his initials into each one of them so they will never ever forget.
我被吸收进兄弟会后
After I was recruited into the Fraternity,
在那联邦法官被杀之前几个礼拜
I found out that Max Petridge's name had come up
麦克斯·佩特里吉的名字就出现过
weeks before the federal judge was killed,
但当时的兄弟会成员却下不了手杀他
and that a Fraternity member had failed to pull the trigger.
我不知道我们做的决定对未来的影响有多深远
We don't know how far the ripples of our decisions go.
也许你杀一个人
You kill one, and maybe,
可以救一千人
save a thousand.
那就是兄弟会的法规
That's the code of the Fraternity.
那正是我们所相信的  所以我们才做这些事
That's what we believe in, and that's why we do it.
现在
Now!
十字架
Cross.
还没
Not yet.
你的目标将会在一台黑色豪华轿车里
Your target will be in a black limo.
他的车会在哈士德路上行经六个路口
He always travels the same six blocks of Halsted.
你有三个路口的时间杀他
You have three blocks to kill him.
妈的
Shit.
对不起
I'm sorry.
巴里你能喂下安娜蓓尔吗
CATHY: Barry! Could you feed Annabelle?
巴里
Barry!
韦斯利  你跑哪去了  我很想念你  老弟
Wesley. Hey, where have you been? I have really missed you, man.
瞧你这好汉  操你妈的混蛋  怎么
Look at the big man. You fucking asshole! What?
怎么你失踪了几个礼拜
What? You don't show up for weeks,
现在只是来借个厕所
now you're just gonna stop by and use the bathroom?
你以为你是什么大人物了  是吧
You think you're a real big shot now, huh?
不  你知道吗  你什么屁都不是
No. You know what? You are nothing!
不  你连屁都不如
No, you are less than nothing.
你比半个巴里都不如
You're not even half the man that Barry is.
巴里至少能让我享受到  你想像不到的快乐
Barry, he pleases me in ways that you've never even heard of!
她是谁  韦斯利  你的新婊子
Who the hell is she, Wesley? Your new whore?
你堕落到这种程度需要花钱买了
Is that what it takes now? You're paying for it?
韦斯利
Wesley?
他是好汉
He's the man.
你还好吗  还好
You all right? Yeah.
我没事  坐下  我帮你找台车
Yeah. I'm okay. Go sit down. I'm gonna find a car.
今晚很重要  我必须去康复室
Big night. I got to get into recovery.
妈的
Shit.
操
Fuck!
正中红心
Bull's -eye.
他在这干嘛
What's he doing here?
拜托  拜托  振作点
Come on! Come on. Just stay with us.
把他的夹克拉下
Pull back his jacket.
呼吸  呼吸
Breathe. Breathe, all right?
没事的  没事的  没事的
It's all right. It's all right. It's all right.
一千
A thousand.
拜托
Come on!
拜托  不  不  别死
Come on! No! No! Stay with us.
拜托  张开你的眼睛
Come on.Open your eyes!
快呀
Come on!
拜托
这颗子弹是他使用过的第一颗  能够追踪到来源的子弹
This bullet is the first traceable bullet he's ever used.
是这个人制造的  他叫沛克华斯基
It was made by this man. His name is Pekwarsky.
他的工作地点在东摩拉维亚修道院
He works out of what is now a monastery in Eastern Moravia.
这地方是兄弟会的诞生地
This place is where the Fraternity was born.
他在向我挑衅
He's taunting me.
他在传输一道讯息给我
He's sending me a message.
我也要传个讯息回去
I'm gonna send him one back.
他对你设了陷阱
He's trapping you.
引诱你到他的地盘
Leading you to a place he knows very well.
这些我都知道  我…
Look, I know this. I...
你训练我就是为了这个
This is what you trained me for.
你不能单独行动
You can't go alone.
如果我不单独去他就不会出现  他可不是笨蛋
I go alone or he doesn't show. He's not stupid.
听好  兄弟会的一个成员因我而死
Look, a member of the Fraternity is dead because of me.
好吧
Okay.
去吧
Go.
谢谢
Thank you.
我不认为那是个好主意
I don't think that's a good idea.
你的下个任务
Your next assignment.
沛克华斯基
Pekwarsky?
妈的
Shit.
你在这干嘛
What are you doing here?
把你的枪放下
Lower your gun.
你知道这东西
You recognise this?
这是从我肩膀里取出来的
I pulled this out of my shoulder.
把它弄到我肩膀里的人就是杀我爸爸的人
The guy who put it there killed my father.
我知道子弹是你制造的  告诉我他在哪里
Now, I know you made it, so tell me where he is.
子弹的确是我做的  但我不能为使用它的人负责
I did mould this, but I can't be responsible for the people who use them.
我不管  告诉我他在哪里
I don't give a shit. Tell me where he is.
看看我的手指
Look at my finger.
我可以试着让你们会面
I can try and arrange a meet.
你有没有想过过不同的生活
Have you ever thought about doing things differently?
什么意思
How do you mean?
不知道
I don't know.
做另一个人
Being somebody else.
一个平凡人
Somebody normal.
没有
No.
妈的
Shit.
闪开
Out of the way!
别动
Stay.
嘿
Hey!
他在火车上
He's on the train.
他单独一人
He's alone.
谢谢
Thank you.
对不起  对不起  坐下
Sorry. I'm sorry. Sit down!
先生  坐下没人会受伤
Sir, sit down! Nobody's gonna get hurt.
先生  坐…坐下  先生  坐下
Sir, sit... Sit down! Sir, sit down!
闪开  坐下  坐下  坐下
Get out of the way! Sit down! Stay down! Stay down!
坐下  没事  坐下
Stay down! It's okay! Sit down!
韦斯利
Wesley.
闪开  闪开
Out of the way! Out of the way!
不  不  不
No, no, no!
韦斯利  听我说
Wesley, listen to me.
闭嘴
Shut the fuck up!
你不配跟我说话
You don't get to talk to me.
他们告诉你的都是谎言
Everything they told you was a lie.
闭嘴  你他妈的骗人  闭上你的鸟嘴
Shut up, you lying piece of shit. You shut the fuck up.
你是我儿子
You are my son.
你说什么
What did you say?
你刚说什么
What did you say to me?
是真的
Is it true?
对
Yes.
你为什么要我这么做
Why did you make me do this?
因为你是唯一他杀不了的人
Because you are the only person he wouldn't kill.
你早知道了  他妈的
You knew, God damn it.
你从头就知道
You knew the entire time.
他的名字出现了
Well, his name came up.
你的也是
So did yours.
不  没关系  没事
No, it was okay. Never mind.
不  不  这一切都是乱来
No. No, it was complete shit.
我答应了你父亲把你带回来这里
I promised your father I'd bring you back here.
什么
What the fuck?
他说这是唯一让你相信的方法
He said it was the only way you'd believe.
你爸爸一直都在你身边
Your father was never more than a camera click away.
那是我
That's me.
他是我爸爸
He was my father.
而我杀了他
And I killed him.
对你父亲来说  保护你比自己的生命还重要
To your father, protecting you was worth giving up his life.
保护我
Protect me?
他他妈的差点杀了我
He was trying to fucking kill me!
不  他根本没有要杀你
No. He wasn't trying to kill you.
他是在救你
He was trying to rescue you.
十字架离开兄弟会后
When Cross left the Fraternity,
斯隆找到了你
Sloan hunted you down.
自从狐狸盯上你后  他就一直试着把你从他们身边分开
Ever since Fox had her teeth in you, he's been trying to separate you from them.
你爸爸从来不想让你进兄弟会  韦斯利
Your father never wanted you in the Fraternity, Wesley.
他想给你一个不同的人生
He wanted a different path for you,
给你他永远得不到的东西
with things that he could never have.
一个家
A home.
和平  不
Peace. No.
他希望你能找到自己的前途
He hoped you would find your own way.
你爸爸找到了这个
Your father got hold of this.
你自己解读吧
Decipher it yourself.
斯隆几年前为了私欲开始自己伪造目标
Sloan began manufacturing targets of his own for profit years ago.
你爸爸得知了这件事
Your father found out about it.
他原本想要用自己的方法解决
And he was going to do something about it on his own, right?
但斯隆却说服了所有人敌对他
But Sloan turned everyone against him.
我父亲的名字从来就没出现过  对不对
WESLEY: My father's name never even came up, did it?
因为他遵遁规章反而让他成了目标
No. Holding to the code made him a target.
斯隆
对
Yes.
你要我逃跑  不
You want me to run? No.
我想要你活着
I want you to live.
你可以过着不同的生活  韦斯利
You can have a different life, Wesley.
就如你父亲所希望的
Like your father wanted for you.
我们把他训练得很好
We trained him well.
我爸爸说错了一件事
My father was wrong about one thing.
他们告诉我的并非全部是谎言
Everything they told me wasn't a lie.
他们教我如何杀人  如何抛弃情感
They taught me how to kill, how to feel no pain,
最重要的是  所有的任务都有一个最完美的武器
and most importantly, that every job has a perfect weapon.
我就是那完美的武器
Well, I'm the perfect weapon.
而我现在却要逃跑
And I'm supposed to run?
不  我已经逃避了一辈子
No, I've been doing that my entire life.
所以我拒绝
So I say no.
我要杀了他们  让命运来决定其它的事情
I say kill them all and let fate sort out the mess.
杀了他
Kill him.
他在这里
He's here!
胆小鬼
Pussy.
胆小鬼  胆小鬼
Pussy, pussy.
胆小鬼
Pussy.
斯隆
Sloan!
我爸爸不是叛徒
My father wasn't a traitor.
这是个杀人命令
This is a kill order.
而目标正是斯隆
And it's got Sloan's name on it.
你说过什么
What did you say to me?
是个名字  是个目标
It's a name. It's a target.
我不想要他死
I don't want this person dead.
是命运要他死
Fate does.
命运要你死
Fate wanted you dead.
他无法接受
And he couldn't take it.
所以他开始伪造一些目标来图利
So he started manufacturing his own targets for his own gains.
我爸得知了这件事  而决定与他对抗
And that's when my dad found out and decided to stand against him.
而你就利用他的儿子
And that's when you sent a man's son
去杀了自己的爸爸
to kill his father.
你不是命运的剌客  斯隆
You're not an assassin of fate, Sloan.
你只是个能让子弹转弯的坏人
You're just a thug who can bend bullets.
是真的吗
Is that true?
事实是这样的
Here is what the truth is.
你的名字出现了
Your name came up.
你的名字
Your name.
你的
Yours.
这房里的所有人
Everyone in this room.
如果我当时没那么做
If I had not done what I did,
你们都已经死了
you would all be dead.
我救了你们的命
I saved your lives.
看看现在的我们  比以往更加强大
Now look where we are. We are stronger than ever.
用我们的能力改变历史
Changing the course of history as we see it.
我们自己决定目标
Choosing the targets we select.
将权力分配到需要的地方
We can redistribute power where we see fit.
这是强者生存的世界
The wolves rule.
弱者只能死去
Not the sheep.
如果你们认为必须完全
Now, if any of you feel the need to follow the code
遵照兄弟会的规章
of the Fraternity to the letter,
那请你们举起枪
I invite you to take your gun,
放到自己的嘴里  然后扣下扳机
put it in your mouth and pull the trigger.
那是韦斯利想要的
That is what Wesley demands.
否则
Otherwise,
杀了这他妈的混蛋
shoot this motherfucker
让我们把兄弟会杀手带上前所未有的高度
and let us take our Fraternity of Assassins to heights
一个只适合神的高度
reserved only for the gods of men.
你的选择
You choose.
去他妈的规章
Fuck the code.
斯隆
Sloan!
六个礼拜前  我只是个平凡无奇的人
Six weeks ago, I was ordinary and pathetic.
就像你
Just like you.
但现在呢
But who am I now?
是帐户经理
Account manager?
杀手
Assassin?
或只是一个被利用来杀死自己父亲的工具
Or just another tool who was mind-fucked into killing his father?
我都是
I am all of these.
也都不是
And I am none of these.
我现在是谁
Who am I now?
我并没有达成我的使命
This is not me fulfilling my destiny.
我并没有追随父亲的脚步
This is not me following in my father's footsteps.
我也绝对没有拯救世界
This is definitely not me saving the world.
还想知道你是谁
Still trying to figure out who you are?
这不是我
This is not me.
这是另一个他妈的圈套
This is just a motherfucking decoy.
操
Oh, fuck.
这是我控制情势
This is me taking control.
不被斯隆
From Sloan,
不被兄弟会
from the Fraternity,
不被珍妮丝  不被报表
from Janice, from billing reports,
不被人体工学键盘
from ergonomic keyboards,
不被劈腿女友  不被假惺惺的挚友所控制
from cheating girlfriends and sack-of-shit best friends.
这是我再一次重新掌握
This is me taking back control
自己的人生
of my life.
你最近做了些什么
What the fuck have you done lately?